<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Kreydt</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2024-03-06T20:56:37-05:00</updated>
 <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Kreydt</name>
   <email>none@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The Difference Between Meditation and Contemplation</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/meditation-contemplation"/>
   <updated>2024-02-20T17:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/meditation-contemplation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is an important difference between meditation and contemplation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the many beautiful traditions handed down through the Catholic faith, we have meditation and contemplation. In fact, these processes are traditional to many human cultures. One might call them universal. In recent times, even scientists have adopted and studied the effects of meditation and contemplation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the two processes are often misunderstood or wrongly defined. Misunderstanding leads to untruth. Untruth is the opposite of Christ who is “the way and &lt;em&gt;the truth&lt;/em&gt; and the life.” (John 14:6) The opposite of Christ is the Antichrist, spiritual tragedy, Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we want to practice meditation and contemplation in truth, then we must know what each one is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcomes of many prayers, rites, and sacramentals, of the Church depend on the practitioner knowing the meaning of and understanding their words. For example, the process for praying Lectio Divina includes a &lt;em&gt;meditation&lt;/em&gt; piece and also a &lt;em&gt;contemplation&lt;/em&gt; piece. Mixing up the definitions of those two words significantly changes how Lectio Divina is prayed. This could result in further misunderstandings and unexpected outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those reasons, I am compelled to define meditation and contemplation, and explain why the definitions I provide are their true definitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;many-popular-websites-and-blogs-present-the-wrong-definitions-of-meditation-and-contemplation-a-few-get-them-right&quot;&gt;Many popular websites and blogs present the wrong definitions of meditation and contemplation. A few get them right.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a quick web search, from which I simply pulled the top results, I found several incorrect definitions of the words meditation and contemplation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20230303114315/https://mindfulnessbox.com/meditation-vs-contemplation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;mindfulnessbox.com&lt;/a&gt;, author Ryan Kane mixes up the definitions of the two words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He writes, “The main difference between contemplation and meditation is that meditation is a practice that focuses on clearing the mind, while contemplation is a more analytical and reflective practice that involves thinking deeply about a particular topic or concept.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In truth, contemplation deals with clearing the mind while meditation involves deep thought; just the opposite of what Kane wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can also see mix-ups and mis-definitions in responses on the popular forums, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/lawofone/comments/17t9o3d/what_is_the_difference_between_meditation_and/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-difference-between-prayer-contemplation-and-meditation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Reddit, user &lt;em&gt;greenraylove&lt;/em&gt; writes, “Meditation is quieting the brain entirely,” but in truth, meditation involves thought, so the brain is not entirely quiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Quora, user &lt;em&gt;J.&lt;/em&gt; writes, “Contemplation is thinking and reflecting with the mind. Meditation is listening.” Again, the two terms are confused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sandra Anderson, in an article published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://yogainternational.com/article/view/contemplation-vs.-meditation-defining-the-difference/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;yogainternational.com&lt;/a&gt;, also mixes the two words up. She writes, “While contemplation is a train of thought about something, meditation is training the mind to rest in a particular focus that leads to a connection to the source of consciousness itself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, meditation involves thought, seeking to understand. Contemplation involves restful watching, listening. Sandra has written the opposite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a Christian spiritual direction website called &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20231004041350/https://anamchara.com/the-difference-between-meditation-and-contemplation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;anamchara.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;someone seems to have finally written the truth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is there that Carl McColman writes, “this kind of meditation is a process of cognitive, mental engagement,” and “In contemplation, we seek to make ourselves radically available for the presence of God.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another truthful answer is given by Sister Mary Colombiere on &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20231204035027/https://carmelitesistersocd.com/2013/meditation-contemplation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;carmelitesistersocd.com&lt;/a&gt;. She writes, “the basic difference between meditation and contemplation is that meditation is a human mode of prayer whereas contemplation is divinely infused prayer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to see that some writers tell the truth. At the same time, the internet is seething with lies. So how do you know I, myself, am not lying or accidentally providing incorrect information?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-can-find-the-true-meanings-of-the-words-by-tracing-them-back-to-their-roots&quot;&gt;We can find the true meanings of the words by tracing them back to their roots.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking, “who is this guy to say which definition is true and which one is false?” That is a valid concern. Why should you trust me? What is the source of my information? How do I know which definition is right and which one is wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I came to the true definitions of contemplation and meditation: I researched the etymology of the two words. In the etymology, we trace words back to their roots. By looking at their roots, we can often determine their true definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially true when it comes words like meditation and contemplation which a) have roots in Latin, and b) are used in instructions that were also originally written in Latin, like those of Lectio Divina. By understanding what the word means in Latin, we can understand what the author, writing in Latin, meant when he used the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-etymology-indicates-that-meditation-involves-thought-while-contemplation-involves-observation&quot;&gt;The etymology indicates that meditation involves thought while contemplation involves observation.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meditation comes from the Latin word meditationem. Meditationem is defined at &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20240204131931/https://www.etymonline.com/word/meditation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;etymonline.com&lt;/a&gt; as “a thinking over, meditation,” “to meditate, think over, reflect, consider,” and “take appropriate measures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the etymology, we see that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;meditation involves thought.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contemplation comes from the Latin word contemplationem. Contemplationem is defined at &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20231223205157/https://www.etymonline.com/word/contemplation#etymonline_v_18269&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;etymonline.com&lt;/a&gt; as the “act of looking at,” “to gaze attentively, observe; consider, contemplate,” and “to mark out a space for observation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the etymology, we see that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;contemplation involves observation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;proper-definition-and-understanding-of-the-words-we-use-are-essential&quot;&gt;Proper definition and understanding of the words we use are essential.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mixing the definitions of words, or not taking care to properly understand them, can lead well-meaning people to misguide themselves and others. Who knows what destructive effects result from such misunderstanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, to any of us who sincerely seek truth and understanding, the Lord will meet us where our knowledge falls short. Nonetheless, faith alone will not suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we do not understand the words of Christ and his bride, the Church, then the words don’t matter. I can read that “love is patient” a million times, but if I do not understand the meaning of the word patient, then I am at risk of misunderstanding love altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writings of Scripture were given to us because they matter. The writings of the desert fathers have been handed down for hundreds of years because they matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words matter, and so I will leave you with the words (shared on &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20220330013657/https://www.thomasmertonnyc.org/about-merton/explore/2016/7/5/the-contemplative&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;thomasmertonnyc.org&lt;/a&gt;) of the renowned and beloved Trappist monk, mystic, and author, Thomas Merton, who knew the true definitions of contemplation and meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;”Contemplation is the highest expression of man’s intellectual and spiritual life…It is spiritual wonder. It is spontaneous awe at the sacredness of life, of being. It is a vivid realization of the fact that life and being in us proceed from an invisible, transcendent and infinitely abundant source. Contemplation is, above all, awareness of the reality of that source.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;”To meditate is to exercise the mind in serious reflection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Get the Most Out of Your Journaling Practice</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/journaling-tips"/>
   <updated>2024-01-09T17:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/journaling-tips</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have been journaling since 2001. This is how I use the habit to my advantage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-scientific-evidence-of-journalings-benefits-looks-promising&quot;&gt;The Scientific Evidence of Journaling’s Benefits Looks Promising&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There exists an abundance of scientific evidence showing the benefits of journaling, especially for specific journaling protocols.&lt;/strong&gt; Neuroscientist Andrew Huberman discussed one of them on his podcast (linked below). It’s a fascinating episode, but as with most scientific expositions, it both oversells and undersells the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science oversells because it looks at groups instead of individuals. A statement like, “more than 200 quality peer-reviewed studies…reveal that the positive physical shifts that occur in people that complete this [protocol] are both significant and long-lasting,” makes journaling seem very powerful, but there are many complexities and confounding factors when looking at these outcomes. And many people don’t fit into the average. There are outliers to whom the evidence does not hold true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scientific discussion also undersells. It fails to mention any benefits that cannot be quantified or measured. Science does not provide an individual’s perspective and observations. For that reason, I want to share some of my own thoughts on journaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-own-introduction-to-journaling&quot;&gt;My Own Introduction to Journaling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My story begins with English class way back in 2001. I wasn’t even a teenager yet. My English teacher would have the class sit in silence for ten or fifteen minutes and write anything we wanted. In those journaling sessions, I discovered my passion for writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked forward to those few minutes when I could escape into myself and write about the colorful trees I had seen on a bike ride or my plans for summer vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That experience ignited a habit that I have continued ever since. Now, journaling has been with me through all the ups and downs of my life, the good times and the bad times. This leads me to my first point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;journaling-is-not-a-magic-bullet&quot;&gt;Journaling is Not a Magic Bullet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expressing myself in writing has added value to my life, and I certainly would not call it a waste of time. At the same time, though, &lt;strong&gt;the simple act of writing does not cure mental, physical, or spiritual ailments. In my experience, it can even exacerbate them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journaling is not a magic bullet. It is mirror reflection of the heart. As we write, we are studying that reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If my heart is diseased, my writing will be diseased, and that will reflect again back to my heart. In that case, journaling is no cure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But if I make a small and positive change in the words I write, that change will reflect to my heart.&lt;/strong&gt; Then, the next time I write, the light shining from my heart will be a little brighter and the writing will reflect that. &lt;strong&gt;It can become a beautiful cycle of healing.&lt;/strong&gt; But if the changes I make are negative, or if I have a negative mindset and write exactly that (changing nothing), then it can be a tragic cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For that reason, we must see journaling not as a cure all, but as a part of the soil in which we grow.&lt;/strong&gt; When our soil is full of rocks and thorns, we do not grow well, but when it is rich with dirt and living organisms, we have the conditions we need to thrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To develop healthy soil, we must journal the right way. So what is the right way to journal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-journal-the-right-way&quot;&gt;How to Journal the Right Way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are a couple requirements in order to journal in a way that promotes health and positivity. First, we need a reason for writing. Second, we must strive to reflect reality with honesty.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;have-a-reason&quot;&gt;Have a Reason&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we have no reason for writing, we will sit down in front of an empty page and fill it with nothing. We must have a reason. There are many possible reasons for journaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some reasons for journaling:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To record a specific memory&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To express feelings about something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To weigh pros and cons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To think through a problem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To plan for the future&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To track progress toward a goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To learn about yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason is, we most likely will not journal to record a fictional story. That would fall under the definition of fiction writing rather than journaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reflect-with-honesty&quot;&gt;Reflect with Honesty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, journaling deals with reality. We might write a poem in a journal, but it is likely going to reflect our own reality rather than a fictional or mythical one. And it wouldn’t really be journaling if we set about writing a piece of fiction. &lt;strong&gt;Because we are dealing with reality when we journal, we should strive to be honest in our writing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honesty is the accurate reflection of reality. It is an excellent guide. As we write honestly about the things of our lives, we have the opportunity to see them with a deeper level of clarity. This leads to the discovery of new insights and revelations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;noticing-and-correcting-the-lies-we-tell-ourselves&quot;&gt;Noticing and Correcting the Lies We Tell Ourselves&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many modern day versions of psychotherapy, which are often used for the same purposes as journaling (e.g. self-discovery, solving problems, achieving goals), center around a patient, who is aided by a therapist, in discovering the lies or inaccuracies in their thoughts and beliefs. The prime example of this is &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Behavioral Therapy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Cognitive Behavioral Therapy&lt;/em&gt;, a patient is taught to disrupt or correct faulty thought patterns known as cognitive distortions. &lt;strong&gt;Cognitive distortions, put simply, are lies we tell ourselves.&lt;/strong&gt; In working with a therapist, the patient learns to catch these lies before they turn into negative emotions or beliefs. With practice, catching and correcting these lies can heal faulty mental programming and disordered thought patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If we pay careful attention as we write about our experiences, we can catch some of our own cognitive distortions.&lt;/strong&gt; This happens organically when we strive to write with honesty. The process might look like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;correcting-cognitive-distortions-an-example&quot;&gt;Correcting Cognitive Distortions, An Example&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kanye West was dating a woman who broke up with him. After telling him it was over, she blocked his phone number so he could no longer get in touch with her. At first glance, the blocking seemed unprovoked. He wasn’t harassing her or anything. He only tried texting her once to apologize for being a jerk. That’s when he found out she had blocked him.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a song about the woman, Kanye wrote, “how could you be so heartless?” In that moment, he was ignoring the complexities of this woman. Instead, he slapped the label, “heartless,” on her. This is a cognitive distortion called “labeling.” It feels good in the moment, but can result in harmful beliefs and unnecessary suffering.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Later, as he was journaling about a date he had with the woman, he recalled that she told him about her ex-boyfriend who was abusive and kept harassing her to the point that she had to get a restraining order on him.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As he wrote honestly about the situation, Kanye realized that the woman’s perspective was very different from his own. Even though he hadn’t provoked her to block his phone number, she had reason to believe it would be the best way to avoid drama. This helped him to see the woman as a human being and to learn from the situation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, that didn’t actually happen - not that I know of - but it gets the point across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kanye’s deeper analysis seems messier and less conclusive than “she’s heartless,” but it is a more accurate reflection of reality. &lt;strong&gt;Life is messy. There are many things we do not know, many mysteries, and when we accept them, when we write them into our stories, we give them an identity. When something has an identity, we can face it, learn from it, and even embrace it. When it doesn’t have an identity, it is a monster; it cannot be faced or embraced.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to help catch cognitive distortions, &lt;a href=&quot;./cognitive-distortions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I made a list (linked here) of common cognitive distortions along with definitions, examples, and ways to correct them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As we embrace honesty in our writing, we begin to see how complex and magical the world is.&lt;/strong&gt; This brings us to the greatest aim of journaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-reason-to-journal&quot;&gt;The Best Reason to Journal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my own experience, facing the complexity and mystery and magic of the world, through honest journaling, brought me to my knees. It terrified me. It made me sick and poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In order to carry on, I had to acknowledge my lack of understanding, my incompleteness of knowledge, my mortality. When I was in that place of weakness and poverty, I needed God. I needed the aid of the one who knows and understands everything that I cannot know or understand.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When I went to him, in faith, that is when journaling really paid off. I went to him and he was there, and he comforted me. I felt peace deeper than any peace I had ever felt before.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can someone go to God without journaling? Yes, of course. But &lt;strong&gt;we can use journaling as a tool to help us get to the truth, and the truth helps us get to God.&lt;/strong&gt; God is The Truth, and what better use is there for journaling than as a means for seeking and discovering him?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I am the way and the truth and the life.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ, John 14:6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;journaling-resources&quot;&gt;Journaling Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./cognitive-distortions&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cognitive Distortions and How to Fix Them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hubermanlab.com/episode/a-science-supported-journaling-protocol-to-improve-mental-physical-health&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Andrew Huberman podcast - A Science-Supported Journaling Protocol to Improve Mental and Physical Health&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cognitive Distortions and How to Fix Them</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/cognitive-distortions"/>
   <updated>2023-12-30T17:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/cognitive-distortions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ways we deceive ourselves and how we can find the truth&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Above all, don’t lie to yourself. The man who lies to himself and listens to his own lie comes to a point that he cannot distinguish the truth within him, or around him, and so loses all respect for himself and for others. And having no respect he ceases to love.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Fyodor Dostoevsky, The Brothers Karamazov&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cognitive distortions are ways we deceive ourselves. These lies, that we tell ourselves and believe, cause all sorts of suffering and pain. With practice, though, we can catch them and correct them. We can develop an honest, undistorted way of seeing the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we see a situation with unclouded eyes, our beliefs about it change, and when our beliefs change, our feelings change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if I have $5 and I believe I need $10 to be prepared, then I feel unprepared. If I have $5 and I believe I only need $1 to be prepared, then I feel prepared. I have the same amount either way, but my feelings differ because my beliefs differ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all truths, there is beauty and goodness, so when we get to the truth, we increase our sense of peace and joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are nine common cognitive distortion and how to correct each of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-or-nothing-thinking&quot;&gt;All-or-Nothing Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All-or-nothing thinking is viewing things as though there were only two possible categories. Quite often, this thought pattern does not reflect reality, therefore it is a distortion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of all-or-nothing thinking: “I had a headache and it ruined my whole day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, we can reflect on the grey areas and complexities in the situation or object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I had a headache. It hurt, but I laughed when grandma farted, and I got some grocery shopping done.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overgeneralizing&quot;&gt;Overgeneralizing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overgeneralizing is viewing a single negative event as a never-ending pattern of defeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of overgeneralizing: “I always get the slowest line in the grocery store.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, we can think of a specific and concrete exception to the generalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I got the slowest line at the grocery store today, but I did get a fast one at Ralph’s last Saturday.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mental-filtering&quot;&gt;Mental Filtering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental filtering is viewing the negative aspects of a situation while ignoring or filtering out the positive aspects of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of mental filtering: “He said he doesn’t like my haircut.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, we can think about the parts of the situation that we are filtering out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He said he doesn’t like my haircut, but that I am beautiful even with a bad haircut.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mind-reading&quot;&gt;Mind Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mind reading is assuming you know what someone is thinking or feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of mind reading: “She hasn’t texted back. She must be mad at me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, think of alternative possibilities and/or communicate with the person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She hasn’t texted back. Maybe she is busy with work. Maybe she dropped her phone in the toilet. Maybe she is driving.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or communicate: “hey, I thought I would have heard back from you by now. Is everything okay?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fortune-telling&quot;&gt;Fortune Telling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortune telling is predicting that things will turn out in a negative way and you won’t be able to cope with the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of fortune telling: “I am going to trip on stage or something. I just know it. Everybody will be embarrassed for me. It’ll be so awkward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, consider the likelihood of your prediction, and then plan for the worst case scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have practiced a ton, so I am less likely to make a mistake. If I do make a mistake, the very worst case is that I will be fired and then not be able to find another job and lose my apartment and end up homeless and have to start from scratch. If that happens, I will start by spending two hours at the library each day applying for jobs.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;magnifying-or-minimizing&quot;&gt;Magnifying or Minimizing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magnifying or minimizing is overvaluing or undervaluing the importance of a situation or fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the fifth time I’ve been rejected. It’s shameful to have been rejected so many times.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, look at the situation or fact from different perspectives. How will it look in a month, in a year, on your deathbed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In a month, I might be rejected three more times, and then five won’t seem nearly as shameful. In a year, I might actually be accepted by someone, especially if I can get these cognitive distortions under control, and then the rejections won’t matter so much. On my deathbed, I’ll be glad I at least tried, and surely I’ll have some successes to look back on, and I’ll have nurses who care for me all day long, and soon I will be even closer to God, who loves his children.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emotional-reasoning&quot;&gt;Emotional Reasoning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emotional reasoning is assuming that how you feel is an accurate reflection of how things are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of emotional reasoning: “I feel anxious. That must mean something bad is going to happen.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, realize that emotions are influenced by beliefs. Our unique perspectives in regards to the facts shape our beliefs about the facts, and our beliefs shape our emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I feel anxious, but it’s not necessarily because something bad is going to happen. It is because I believe something bad is going to happen. Why do I believe that? What are the facts about the situation?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shoulds-musts-and-have-tos&quot;&gt;Shoulds, Musts, and Have-Tos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shoulds, musts, and have-tos are the beliefs that things should or shouldn’t, must or mustn’t, have to or can’t, be a certain way without any evidence to support those claims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An examples of shoulds, musts, and have-tos: “I should start working on this project now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, consider the reasoning, the why, behind the “should,” “must,” or “have to.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I start working on this project now, I will be less stressed as the deadline approaches.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;labeling&quot;&gt;Labeling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Labeling is applying labels or stereotypes to situations, to yourself, or to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of labeling: “I’m late for work again. I’m such a loser!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this type of lie, acknowledge the facts and details instead of simply labelling the situation or person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m late for work again. I forgot to set my alarm.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personalizing&quot;&gt;Personalizing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personalizing is holding yourself accountable for something that isn’t or wasn’t entirely under your control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of personalizing: “She ghosted me because I am an annoying person.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To combat this lie, define healthy boundaries in your relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“She ghosted me because of her own beliefs, feelings, and perspective about the our relationship. I am not responsible for her choices.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note, this is not an exhaustive list of cognitive distortions. There are many more documented in the psychological and scientific literature. However, these are some of the most common cognitive distortions in our culture. Beginning with these nine cognitive distortions can open your heart to many truths it had not previously known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you spend a few minutes every day reviewing the cognitive distortions you commonly falling into, you will grow in your ability to recognize and combat them in the moment. Then you can stop them in their tracks and find greater peace and joy in any situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Carl Jung Resources for Beginners</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/carl-jung-resources"/>
   <updated>2023-10-16T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/carl-jung-resources</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Someone who had trouble understanding Carl Jung asked me for resources. I am documenting them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources-for-learning-jungs-ideas&quot;&gt;Resources for Learning Jung’s Ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jung is not always easy to understand. In fact, he’s usually far from it. His ideas build on one another, so misunderstanding one, or not knowing its meaning, creates a domino effect. That said, he does have a couple works that are on the easier side and work well for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-undiscovered-self&quot;&gt;The Undiscovered Self&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Undiscovered Self is a short and relatively easy read that works as a good introduction into Jung’s world of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mother-archetypes&quot;&gt;Mother Archetypes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sas.upenn.edu/~cavitch/pdf-library/Jung_MotherArchetype.pdf&quot;&gt;This is an interesting, and free, copy of a chapter of one of Jung’s books on archetypes.&lt;/a&gt; It is a good introduction to Jung’s archetype theories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transcripts-of-jungs-talks&quot;&gt;Transcripts of Jung’s Talks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found that reading transcripts of Jung’s talks is a much easier way to understand the man’s ideas in his own words. &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/books/97/09/21/reviews/jung-lecture2.html&quot;&gt;Here is an example of that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;works-edited-by-jung&quot;&gt;Works Edited by Jung&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/B-001-004-443-ALL&quot;&gt;Man and His Symbols, Conceived and Edited by Carl Jung&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man and His Symbols is an excellent way into Jung’s ideas. The book is a compilation of essays by Jung’s contemporaries, edited by Jung himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has some excellent essays that cover a range of Jungian topics, from the symbolism in Beauty and the Beauty to dream analysis to approaching the unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can find it, I highly recommend the old hardcover version (that’s the version I linked to above) that has larger and full-color images. In a book about symbols, big, colorful images really help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;youtube-videos-that-explain-and-quote-jungs-ideas&quot;&gt;YouTube Videos that Explain and Quote Jung’s Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I first came to learn about Jung and his ideas was through one of my favorite YouTube channels: &lt;a href=&quot;https://academyofideas.com/&quot;&gt;Academy of Ideas&lt;/a&gt;. They have a whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WBAFPbypyn4&amp;amp;list=PLAYxecbGotUz1tjZlymlSc30aENg_S0Xp&quot;&gt;playlist of videos&lt;/a&gt; introducing Jung’s ideas. The videos are full of great quotes and wonderful art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;your-own-mind&quot;&gt;Your Own Mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I think you have to do a lot more thinking about Jung’s idea than reading about them. You have to really chew on them; “is this what he meant by that? No, that would contradict this. He must have meant this. Oh wait, this scholar puts it this way. Yes, that seems right, doesn’t it? No, if that’s so, then this could not be.” Eventually, Jung makes you go crazy and his whole purpose is accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;works-by-jungian-scholars&quot;&gt;Works by Jungian Scholars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/details/kingwarriormagic00moor_1&quot;&gt;King Warrior Magician Lover by Robert Moore and Douglas Gillette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;King Warrior Magician Lover is a popular book from the 1990s that gives an interesting persective on Jung’s ideas of archetypes and the shadow. The book describes what the authors call the four masculine archetypes, and each of their shadow archetypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe these archetypes apply to women as well. They are really just personifications of what the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scborromeo.org/ccc/p3s1c1a7.htm&quot;&gt;Catholic Church calls “the cardinal virtues.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book also has a method of shadow work toward its conclusion. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;That part of the book is a gem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; because most sources that offer a method of shadow work (e.g. the shadow work journals you might find on Amazon) were created by people who have no real understand of Jungian psychology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-word-of-caution&quot;&gt;A Word of Caution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many people on the internet who will speak of Jung’s ideas as though they have a strong grasp on them, but miss the mark entirely. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Jung/comments/10ratga/big_5_personality_traits_and_the_shadow/&quot;&gt;This post on Reddit&lt;/a&gt; is a good example of the broad range of beliefs among Jung’s followers. It is also an interesting idea to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;addition&quot;&gt;Addition&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally posted this on Medium.com. There, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sammysue.medium.com&quot;&gt;Samantha Price Fischer&lt;/a&gt; left the following comment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I would say his autobiography “Memories, Dreams, and Reflections” is another beautiful way to get a feel for Jung the man.
It was completed near the end of his life and is excellent as an audible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Integrity: How I Learned to Be Myself</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/integrity"/>
   <updated>2023-10-09T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/integrity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Integrity does not mean acting the same way in every situation. It means adhering to the same values and standards in every situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would I want to be myself? Maybe people don’t like me. Don’t I want to be someone else then? Ah, but there is great danger in changing myself for others. Changing the way I dress so that I can fit in at work may not be a big deal. Changing my values or moral actions so I can fit in at work, that is tragic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is, I was that way for many years. I didn’t know how to be myself. I didn’t know who I was. I didn’t know what I valued or needed or wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By God’s grace, I was knocked down. I was hurt. I realized that I must learn to be myself or risk greater tragedy. Pleasing others doesn’t work. After some major failures, and some deep contemplation to learn from them, I realized why I needed to be myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-reasons-to-be-myself&quot;&gt;Three Reasons to Be Myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Being true to myself, being honest about my values, is a good way to ward off people who won’t accept me for who I am.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not being myself is a good way to lose people who might have actually accepted me for who I am, if they had seen the real me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changing myself to please others is a good way to end up doing something I sincerely regret. I suspect this is a reason why so many Germans allowed and/or participated in the holocaust. They simply wanted to fit in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-thought-experiment&quot;&gt;A Thought Experiment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a serious amount of time thinking about the third reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I wondered this: if a Nazi asked me to turn in all of my Jewish neighbors, would I do it? “No way,” I thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I asked myself: what have I always wanted more than anything in my entire life, but don’t have?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I imagined a person I loved dearly coming to me with great kindness and charisma, and offering me exactly what I’ve always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered what I would do. Would I accept her offer? What if she said I had to betray my best friend in return? Would I still do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I contemplated these questions with honesty. I did not hide my fallen human nature, my selfish tendencies. Then I went further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if she didn’t ask for something as difficult as betraying my best friend? What if she just asked me to turn in all of my Jewish neighbors? People I barely know. I can have exactly what I want if I just tell her where the Jewish people in my neighborhood are hiding. And if I refuse to tell her, then I will not get what I have always wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took it further. If I refuse to tell her where my Jewish neighbors were hiding, then she would take my life. Would I turn my neighbors in if I were offered such a thing? Would I betray my deepest values?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could I resist? I would need a damn good reason. I might even need access to the peace and joy of Heaven in order to find the fortitude to pass up the one thing I have always wanted. Only Heaven could be better than that. Only Heaven could give me the strength to give up a life of whatever I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The kingdom of heaven is at hand.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem-with-just-being-myself&quot;&gt;The Problem with Just Being Myself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The silly little maxim, “just be yourself,” holds some degree of wisdom. Insomuch as it means “do not change yourself in order to impress others,” it is a reasonable thing to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, though, just being myself presents a problem. If I am to just be myself, then what am I to do with my evil traits? What am I to do with the aggression that resulted in me punching a wall and breaking my hand when I was a kid? What am I to do with the disagreeableness that resulted in the demise of so many of my friendships? What is the mother supposed to do when just being herself results in the abuse of her child?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How can I be my true self without committing evil acts when there is indeed evil in me?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution-1-sacrifice-my-morality&quot;&gt;Solution 1: Sacrifice My Morality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I could simply do all the things I feel like doing, whenever I feel like doing them, whether they are evil or not.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could let go of my morals. This would only really work, in the long run, if I was a nihilist. Then I could be myself because my broken hand wouldn’t matter, my friendships wouldn’t matter, the abused child wouldn’t matter. Whatever I would do, it wouldn’t matter. I would have the freedom to be purely myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In regards to this problem of integrity, Carl Jung said, &lt;em&gt;“To destroy a man’s morality does not help either because it would kill his better self…”&lt;/em&gt; (https://archive.nytimes.com/www.nytimes.com/books/97/09/21/reviews/jung-lecture2.html)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I lose my morals, I also lose the best parts of myself. Without morality, my life has no meaning. The meaningful parts of my life are crucified along with my morals, and the meaningful parts are often the best parts. Comforting a friend, saving a life, suffering with dignity; none of these have any value without morality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, giving up my morals is not the answer. Acting on every whim, betraying my values in order to be true to myself ends up devaluing the best parts of my life, the parts with meaning and virtue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution-2-repress-my-selfish-or-undesirable-traits&quot;&gt;Solution 2: Repress My Selfish or Undesirable Traits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I could simply ignore, blind myself to, anything I see as evil in myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option is to approach the problem with repression. I can hide my negative personality traits away. I can even hide them from myself. I can forget that moment in eighth grade when I punched a wall. I can place all the blame on my friends for our relationship issues. I can refuse to believe that I have evil tendencies and reassure myself that I am good person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I am not, at least consciously, doing evil things. But I am not being my true self either, so we still have a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is great strength, great virtue, to be gained in knowing the evils of which I am capable. In fact, if I am incapable of evil, then I have no real virtue at all. I am only good because I have no choice in the matter. That is not virtue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to losing the positive values of my negative traits, such as the ability to protect loved ones that comes with my aggression or the ability to negotiate on their behalf that comes with my disagreeableness, I also run the risk of bursting out in moments of weakness or committing evils without even realizing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“…a practice the Nazis used in training the SS officer corps. The candidates for the corps would raise puppies, caring for them in every way, tending them when they were sick, feeding and grooming them, playing with them. Then, at an arbitrary moment decided upon by the trainer, these men were ordered to kill their puppies, and to do so with no sign of feeling. This training in unfeeling sadism evidently worked well, because these same men became killing machines that manned the death camps — systematically, and without emotion, torturing and murdering millions of human beings while still thinking of themselves as ‘good fellows.’”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Moore and Gillette, King Warrior Magician Lover&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a conundrum. On the one hand, there is honesty in just being myself, doing whatever I want. At least, then, I am not changing myself for others. On the other hand, there are evil parts of myself that must be restrained if my life is to have meaning and value, and if I am to coexist with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Am I doomed to choose between honesty and every other virtue? No.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-better-solution&quot;&gt;A Better Solution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;live-my-life-by-an-ethic&quot;&gt;Live My Life By an Ethic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a better solution than immorality or repression. There is ethic. Abiding by an ethic enables me to live with integrity while restraining my evil traits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can I live an honest and integrated life if I am restraining a part of myself, though? I can do it by exercising a uniquely human power that is a part of myself: the ability to make a moral decision before acting or reacting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a question and answer video from January 2018 (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1pNn91Ewzbc), someone asked the psychologist, Jordan B. Peterson, his thoughts on healthy expression of sexuality. Peterson’s answer, though it is specific to sexual repression, applies to the problem addressed in this writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question was, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;“how can we know the difference between unhealthy repression and healthy self-restraint of sexuality?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some talk about the ethics of sex, Peterson got to the point that answers the problem I have laid out in this writing. He said, “there’s the necessity to forgo immediate gratification for the purpose of medium-to-long term thriving. So if your sexuality is integrated in an ethic that encompasses the rest of your life, and if it serves that ethic, then I would say it’s properly restrained. If it’s unhealthily repressed, then you’re angry and bitter and resentful.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can substitute any personality trait for sexuality. Peterson’s answer still applies. For example, if my aggression is integrated in an ethic that encompasses the rest of my life, and if it serves that ethic, then it is properly restrained. I can still act on my aggression, but before I do, I must stop to decide whether using my aggression in that scenario fits into my ethic. In that case, I can avoid the resentment that comes with unhealthy repression because I am doing what I choose, not what some rule or authority has chosen for me. Thus, I avoid the classic “pushover holds in anger until he explodes” scenario. At the same time, I am maintaining my morality and being myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Peterson is saying that if I restrain a trait for a reason that is so important to me that it applies to every part of my life, then that is proper restraint. If I restrain my disagreeableness in regards to a small argument because my relationship with my best friend is so important that it applies to every part of my life, that is not a sacrifice of my integrity. It is a proper ordering of and acting upon what I value most. When my values are ordered and my actions align with that, then I have true integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would actually be less myself if I were to sacrifice my relationship with my best friend in order to allow myself to be disagreeable on a whim. I would be destroying a part of myself that I value greatly, my ability to make sacrifices for my friends, for something that I value less, my ability to disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fits with Jung’s teaching that “a mere suppression of the shadow is just as little of a remedy as beheading against headache.” Mere suppression is no remedy to an imbalanced personality trait, but recognizing one’s shadow and then restraining certain traits for a good reason, like adherence to a life-encompassing ethic, might just work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;living-with-integrity-while-not-acting-on-every-whim&quot;&gt;Living with Integrity While Not Acting on Every Whim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To live with integrity, I must know the reasons for my actions. This is no easy task. How do I know if I am truly giving to the poor because I want what is best for the poor? Maybe I am doing it because I believe I am building up good karma for myself. I must know myself as well as possible. I must know my evil tendencies, know what I am capable of, and know my weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I must do everything I can to act consciously and morally. I must, in each moment, strive to know what I am doing and why I decided to do it. I must act because I believe that my action is the best action for me to take. I can do that by adhering to an ethic, a set of morals and values, that I believe is the proper way to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I act because I made a moral decision to act, then I am acting with intent instead of acting on autopilot. If my morality is built on a solid foundation, if it is built upon Truth, then it will never change. And if I am faithful to my unchanging morals, then I have integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Integrity means adhering to the same values and standards in every situation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Living by an ethic, that is how I can “just be myself” without acting on every whim or feeling. Many evils can be overcome in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have integrity when all of the parts of myself are integrated. The way I integrate all of my parts is by directing them all toward an ethic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, they sail like a fleet of ships guided to the same location by the same compass and map. They do not veer off or collide. The fleet that is my self sails with integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is pretty simple. Know my core values and beliefs, act with intent, and do not act contrary to my values and beliefs. Find a way of life with enough meaning that it can justify healthy restraint of my vices.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I Stopped Using Map Apps for a Month</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/quitting-map-apps"/>
   <updated>2023-10-02T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/quitting-map-apps</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of an ongoing effort to slow myself down, to “stop and smell the roses” more often, I quit using map apps on my phone for one month. I learned a few things along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most surprising was that I felt less rushed. I can’t quite explain it, but somehow I felt less rushed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it has to do with the cost of using these devices and apps that have become our world. They cost us our attention. We must give it to them in order to extract any value from them. And when our attention is directed at a tool, or directed at our destination but filtered through a tool, we feel some level of stress. Maybe it’s just the stress of having one more thing to do as we’re heading out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I didn’t use the map app, I didn’t just avoid one step. I avoided several steps. I kept my attention directed at my destination instead of being pulled in multiple directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of picking up my phone to open the app, getting distracted by some other notification or app, finally opening the map app, entering my destination, getting distracted by another notification, checking my estimated arrival time, and then deciding exactly when I needed to leave in order to arrive exactly five minutes early, I just left as early as I could so that I would not be late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I ended up losing a few minutes a few times per week by arriving at places early. Yes, I ended up getting lost and arriving a few minutes late at times. But I had no choice other than to accept those things, and having no choice in a prison of choices is like that first breath of fresh air when the prison doors are opened and you are set free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left my place, got in my car, drove to my destination, and walked in without being distracted by anything on my phone. It seems that the attention, peace, and perhaps even the freedom, I had given up in exchange for easy navigation was of far greater value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another surprising discovery was that, after a year of living in Pittsburgh, I know the city far better than I thought. Maybe that is how these apps hold our attention. They provide us with value so we keep using them, and then we forget we can live without them. It turns out, I was able to find my way to almost any place in the city without using a map app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learned some practical things that might be helpful for anyone who would like to try the experiment, and I highly recommend trying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Watch for one-way streets. A few times, I used my computer to look up directions to a destination, and then wrote the directions down in a notebook. However, on my way back home, I realized that one of the streets I came from was a one-way street, so I couldn’t go back the same way I came. Instead, I had to find another way which is not always easy in a city like Pittsburgh where the streets are not laid out in nice blocks or squares.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you do get lost, the trick is to remember landmarks and keep circling until you get back on track. When you see a landmark, you will know whether or not you already surveyed that area for the street you are looking for; “there’s that church, so I already tried that street and it wasn’t the right way. Next, I’ll try this other street.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pay attention to the name of the street you are on. It was not as hard to remember directions as I thought it would be, but as a consequence of nobody needing to know street names anymore, many intersections do not have street signs. It helps to get in the habit of spotting them when they are there at one intersection because you may not get them at the next.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right at end of the challenge, I was on my way to church. As though God wanted to remind me of the blessings that he can bestow on us through our tools, I ran into a situation in which several roads were closed for a 5k race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed by one closed street, thinking, “I’ll just take the next one over,” only to find that it was closed to, and so was the next one. After some hesitation, I realized I would be late for Mass, where I was scheduled to sing in the choir, if I just tried to find my way instead of using the map app on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave in. I used the map app. I arrived at Mass just in time. The benefit of using the app was worth the cost that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attention is in high demand. Whether app creators are intentionally vying for that attention or not, they captivate us. Quite often, they hold us captive. Typically, they want to. It’s how they make money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the cost of using an app is the loss of freedom or the diminishment of morality - both of which occur readily once our attention is held captive - then the cost outweighs the benefits. If we are careful about how and when we use our devices, about the attention we give them, then perhaps we can maintain our freedom and morality and still have the benefits they provide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is that we remain watchful and intentional so that we continue to own our tools rather than allowing our tools, or their inventors, to own us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fear Without Courage Produces Puppets</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/oppressors-feed-on-fear"/>
   <updated>2023-09-25T18:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/oppressors-feed-on-fear</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You must have courage if you are to avoid being someone’s puppet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If they know your deepest fear, and you lack the courage to face it, evil ones can manipulate you. They only need to do one of two things: promise to free you from your fear without the need for courage or force you to face your fear so that you will do anything to get them to stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through observation and science, we have learned that most humans have the same fears. Most humans fear at least one of the following: aging, death, germs, psychosis, isolation, spiders/mice/snakes/critters, and public speaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By exploiting those fears, individuals can control other individuals and, now that broadcasting of messages exists (it didn’t exist for most of human existence), individuals can control masses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also learned how to destroy someone’s courage. It’s quite simple, really. Courage, like any virtue or muscle, is lost when it is not practiced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To destroy their courage, give people every reason to not face their fears. Hide death, aging, and psychosis away in hospitals and nursing homes, out of sight, out of mind. Hide germs behind sanitization and masks and vaccinations. Hide isolation and public speaking behind the veils of social media and broadcasting. Keep pests away with all sorts of chemicals and traps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we have a whole bunch of puppets. Are you one of them?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>An AI-Generated Blog Post About Why AI Cannot Replace Poets</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/ai-on-poets"/>
   <updated>2023-09-18T17:30:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/ai-on-poets</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is a growing concern that artificial intelligence (AI) will eventually replace poets. After all, AI can already generate text, translate languages, and write different kinds of creative content. So why would we need poets anymore?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are 1000 words on why AI will not replace poets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Poetry is about more than just words. It is about emotion, experience, and connection. AI can generate text, but it cannot generate emotion. It cannot understand what it means to feel love, loss, joy, or sorrow. And it cannot connect with readers on a personal level.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Poetry is about creativity. AI can be used to generate new ideas, but it cannot come up with original ideas. It cannot think outside the box or challenge the status quo. And it cannot create something truly new and innovative.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Poetry is about beauty. AI can generate text that is grammatically correct and factually accurate, but it cannot generate text that is beautiful. It cannot capture the beauty of nature, the beauty of love, or the beauty of the human spirit. And it cannot create something that is truly moving and inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Poetry is about humanity. AI can generate text that is about humans, but it cannot generate text that is truly human. It cannot understand what it means to be human, to experience the world, to feel emotions, and to make choices. And it cannot create something that is truly relatable and meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, AI cannot replace poets because poetry is about more than just words. It is about emotion, creativity, beauty, and humanity. And these are things that AI cannot replicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, AI can be a useful tool for poets. It can be used to generate ideas, to research topics, and to experiment with different forms and styles. But it cannot replace the human element of poetry. It cannot replace the poet’s unique perspective, their personal experiences, and their creative vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while AI may be able to generate text that is grammatically correct and factually accurate, it will never be able to replace poets. Poets are artists, and artists are human. And that is something that AI can never replicate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Living Slowly</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/slow-living"/>
   <updated>2023-09-11T17:30:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/slow-living</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s so easy to get caught up in the bustle, to get in a rush, to turn on autopilot and just do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in that mode for a few days, and then I got a headache, and I started thinking, “what does this headache mean? Am I sick? Am I dying? Can I make it go away before the concert tonight? Should I take ibuprofen or acetaminophen or naproxen sodium or aspirin? Should I have something more natural? Have I not been eating healthy enough? Should I have more coffee? Was my headache caused by drinking too much coffee?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in the middle of this rush, driving back from the grocery store, when traffic slowed down and I saw a young couple with a baby in a stroller, and they were walking slowly. They really stood out against all the rushing cars and red lights and green lights and rushing people on the sidewalks. They were just walking slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was very different than how I usually walk. I walk after I eat, and I walk briskly, to reduce blood sugar spikes. But perhaps it’s not brisk walking and reducing blood sugar spikes that give us health. Perhaps it’s the peace and enjoyment of walking just to walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps not. Perhaps it really is healthier to focus on reducing blood sugar and getting two hours of exercise per week. But even if it is healthier, is it better? Is it happier? Does it improve our quality of life or just give us the promise of additional years?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Live fast if you’d like. But at least stop to ask if that way makes you happy. As for me, living slow in a world of instant gratification, constant rushing, and pervasive stimulation, is a difficult but beautiful skill and a powerful rebellion.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Faithfulness Explained by a Genius Philosopher</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/faithfulness-explained"/>
   <updated>2023-07-06T17:30:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/faithfulness-explained</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those having a difficult time understanding or experiencing faith, I highly recommend starting with an understanding of &lt;em&gt;faithfulness&lt;/em&gt; as defined by Dietrich von Hildebrand, one of the most underrated philosophers of our time. Faithfulness is not quite the same thing as faith, but it is a step towards it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t add much to the text below because Hildebrand wrote it with such elegance. I doubt I could do any better. However, I added a few notes in parentheses and italics. The rest of the quotes are from Dietrich von Hildebrand’s book, &lt;em&gt;The Art of Living&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dietrich-von-hildebrand-on-faithfulness&quot;&gt;Dietrich von Hildebrand on Faithfulness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How many people there are who are never lastingly influenced by great works of art, or by delight in beautiful landscapes, or by contact with great personalities. The momentary impression may be strong, but it strikes no deep root in them; it is not firmly held in their superactual life but disappears as soon as another impression makes its appearance. These men are like a sieve through which everything runs. Though they can be good, kindly, and honest, they cleave to a childish, unconscious position; they have no depth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Such people are continually in danger of becoming traitors to themselves or to others.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, “the persevering man holds on to everything that has revealed itself to him as a true, genuine value. The advantage of liveliness that the present possesses over the past has no power over his life when compared with the inner weight of deep truths that he has once recognized, and of values that he has once grasped. The importance of the role played by a given thing in his present consciousness is exclusively determined by the height of its value, and in no way by its mere presence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Such men are consequently protected from the tyranny of fashion. A thing never makes a deep impression upon them merely because it is modern, because it is momentarily ‘in the air,’ but only because it has a value, because it is beautiful, good, and true.” &lt;em&gt;(notice Hildebrand’s mention of the transcendentals)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The lives of these men are meaningfully integrated, and in their course reflect the objective gradation of values.” &lt;em&gt;(this is a beautiful definition of integrity, more elegant and clear than Jung’s definition)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While the inconstant man is a prey to accidental impressions and situations, the constant man dominates his own impressions.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“[Men with integrity] understand that an important truth is not less interesting and less worthy of concern because we have known it for a long time. They understand, above all, that the obligation to respond to a good possessing a value is not limited to the moment in which it is grasped.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He alone for whom values never lose their efficacy and charm, once they have been revealed to him, and who never lets a truth which he has grasped drop into oblivion, will really do justice to the proper character of the world of truth and values; for he alone is capable of remaining faithful to objects possessing value.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This constancy or fidelity in the true sense of the world is, as we see, a fundamental moral attitude of man.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He alone will stand firm in trials.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It is so because this man lives from the depth, and masters every moment from the depth.” &lt;em&gt;(this is very similar to Jordan Peterson saying one should be guided by an ethic, a way of life)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He will learn from every situtation of life and will grow in every situation, for in him the measure of genuine values remains alive; while the inconstant man yields now to one, now to another impression, and becomes so entirely a prey of each that in the depth of his soul everything passes on more or less without leaving a trace.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The constant man alone will prefer what is more important to what is less so, what is more valuable to the less, while the unstable person will at best respond indiscriminately to all values, recognizing no hierarchy in them. Nothing is, in fact, more important for moral growth, for the very moral life of a person, than consideration for the objective hierarchy of values, and the capacity to give priority to that which is objectively higher.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But constancy is also a condition for any confidence on the part of the person himself and above all for heroic faith. The unstable man is not only undeserving of confidence, but he himself will be incapable of a firm, unshakable confidence either in other men, in truth, or in God Himself.” &lt;em&gt;(confidence in God is also known as faith, so Hildebrand is saying integrity/constancy, faithfulness, is a prerequisite to faith)&lt;/em&gt; “For such a man lacks the strength to nourish his soul upon a value once discovered. Therefore, when night and obscurity surround him, or when other strong impressions assail him, he loses faith. It is no accident that in Latin the word fides means both fidelity and faith. For constancy is an essential constituent of all capacity to believe, and consequently of all religion.” &lt;em&gt;(in this paragraph, Hildebrand claims that integrity/constancy, faithfulness, is a prerequisite for faith. In other words, a man must abide by a hierarchy of values in order to have faith)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Isn’t Hildebrand brilliant? He offers a very different view — seemingly more in line with the complexities of the individual human being — than modern psychology. Psychology simply says, “the man is high in trait openness,” or “the man is low in neuroticism,” and “he will remain mostly that way for his entire life,” but that is too deterministic. Hildebrand makes the case that one version/trait is better than the other, and it can be developed in any man. Any man can become faithful by learning what things are truly valuable and determining the hierarchy of those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faith is scant in our world. Perhaps it is because we have not learned what is truly valuable, or we have not determined what is most valuable, or we do not value anything enough to follow it all the way to the bitter end. Perhaps being aware of this, we can change, we can become faithful, and we can experience that wonderful virtue called faith.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Miracles</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/miracles"/>
   <updated>2023-01-21T16:30:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/miracles</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve been trying to figure out Carl Jung’s concept of the shadow and how to integrate the traits in my own shadow into my psyche. I searched the internet for movies influenced by Jung’s ideas. One movie that came up in my search was Watchmen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends have always loved the movie and have recommended it to me several times, but I’m usually not into superhero movies, so I never got around to watching it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I learned that it was influenced by Jung’s ideas, and remembered how much my friends loved it, I decided I better give it a shot. After watching it, in addition to many hours spent reading Jung and many hours spent thinking, I still don’t fully understand Jung’s concept of the shadow. I have to wonder if he made it up just to give people an impossible puzzle to solve so that we would always have something to aim for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I have observed that a life directed to an aim is in general better, richer, and healthier than an aimless one, and that it is better to go forwards with the stream of time than backwards against it.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Carl Jung, Structure &amp;amp; Dynamics of the Psyche&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot tell you exactly how Watchmen fits in with Jung other than that it is quite mythical and Jung’s ideas were heavily influenced by mythology. But it’s a good movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One scene especially struck me. The scene is an interaction between two superheroes who were once together in a committed relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man is Dr Manhattan, a nuclear scientist and depressed nihilist. He is fascinated by physics and the nature of the material world, but he has no sense of the spiritual dimension. He is only interested in matter, not consciousness or life or relationships. To a nihilist, everything is meaningless. Everything is just matter. Because he knows basically everything about how the material world works, he has no belief in miracles. He knows that whatever happens, it will abide by the laws of nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman is Silk Spectre. Actually, she’s Silk Spectre II. Her mother was Silk Spectre. I will just call her Silk Spectre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the world is on the brink of nuclear war, Dr Manhattan teleports Silk Spectre to Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mars, the two superheroes get into an argument. Silk Spectre is begging Dr Manhattan to come back to Earth and stop the humans from destroying themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Jon, please. You have to stop this. Everyone will die!” Silk Spectre pleas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And the universe will not even notice.” Dr Manhattan replies, his voice plagued with ennui. “In my opinion, the existence of life is a highly overrated phenomenon. Just look around you. Mars gets along perfectly well without so much as a microorganism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He goes on about the material beauty of Mars and then asks, “how would all of this be greatly improved by an oil pipeline, by a shopping mall?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So it’s too much to ask for a miracle?” Silk Spectre asks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr Manhattan replies, “miracles, by their definition, are meaningless. Only what can happen does happen.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some more arguing, Silk Spectre tells Dr Manhattan to send her back to Earth where she can die along with her mother and friends and the other humans. Dr Manhattan complains that she refuses to see things from his perspective because she is afraid. She tells him she’s not afraid, so he places his hand on her forehead and shows Silk Spectre her life from his perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she sees it, she sees an evil man who tries to rape her mother. She also sees that her mother, at a later time, consented to having sex with that same evil man. That is how she was conceived. The evil man is Edward Blake, one of the Watchmen. Her father was an evil man who tried to rape her mother. Her mother was a woman who knowingly loved a rapist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon seeing this, she collapses and says, “my life is just one big joke.” But Dr Manhattan also has a change of heart when he sees Silk Spectre’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Will you smile if I admit I was wrong?” he asks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“About what?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Miracles. Events with astronomical odds of occurring, like oxygen turning into gold. I’ve longed to witness such an event, and yet I neglect that, in human coupling, millions upon millions of cells compete to create life for generation after generation until finally your mother loves a man - Edward Blake, the Comedian, a man she has every reason to hate. And out of that contradiction, against unfathomable odds, it’s you, only you, that emerged to distill so specific a form from all that chaos. It’s like turning air into gold. A miracle. And so I was wrong. Now dry your eyes and let’s go home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hnUalIsKgNM&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps empathy is the real miracle in all of this - in the encounter between Dr Manhattan and Silk Spectre, and in our own lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human beings have the ability to actually feel another person’s feelings and to understand another person’s thoughts. We don’t have Dr Manhattan’s super powers. We have empathy. We can feel another person’s suffering and shed our own tears. We can feel another person’s success and dance in excitement. We can learn another person’s history and understand why they act the way they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empathy is also a weakness. It is a vector through which many infectious demons, neuroses, and bad ideas can be transmitted. When two people allow themselves to take on one another’s feelings, there is great risk, but if both are committed to truth and integrity and love, there is also great reward. It opens our eyes to the humanness of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Empathy can chip away at the prison walls of nihilism like it did for Dr Manhattan. When he sees the impossibly rare history of Silk Spectre, he realizes that just because something is understood doesn’t mean it is not miraculous. Something can be a miracle even though it is physically possible. And something physically impossible, well, maybe that is each one of our lives. Maybe consciousness (which science still can’t quite understand) defies the laws of nature. Maybe life itself is a miracle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So “dry your eyes for you are life, rarer than a quark and unpredictable beyond the dreams of Heisenberg; the clay in which the forces that shape all things leave their fingerprints most clearly. Dry your eyes.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quentin Tarantino Bible Verses</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/quentin-tarantino-bible-verses"/>
   <updated>2022-11-17T16:30:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/quentin-tarantino-bible-verses</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Quentin Tarantino is a movie director/writer/producer. His movies are often very violent. They’re also really good. The stories are unique. The characters and their interactions are deep. The shots are interesting. The movies feel quite “biblical.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, one of his most popular movies, Pulp Fiction, has a Bible verse in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“And I will strike down upon thee with great vengeance and furious anger those who attempt to poison and destroy my brothers. And you will know I am the Lord when I lay my vengeance upon you.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Ezekiel 25:17&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago a priest challenged me, and everyone else listening to his homily, to read through the Bible cover-to-cover. I accepted the challenge, and have been reading about a chapter a day ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I read, various verses and parts stood out to me. One of my favorite parts is when Jacob is at the well. There is a big stone covering the well. It’s so big that it takes several shepherds to move it. But then comes Rachel. Jacob, for the first time, lays eyes on her. Immediately, he goes up and rolls the stone away by himself. Then he goes over to Rachel, kisses her, and yelps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a boss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I continued reading through the books, I found myself amused by some of the detailed descriptions of gore and other brutal scenes. They reminded me of scenes in Quentin Tarantino movies like Kill Bill and Pulp Fiction. I started collecting them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m up to the book of Psalms now, so there may be more to come, and I may have missed some along the way, but here is what I have for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-kings-930-37&quot;&gt;2 Kings 9:30-37&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death of Jezebel&lt;br /&gt;
Jehu came to Jezreel, and when Jezebel heard of it, she shadowed her eyes, adorned her hair, and looked down from her window. 31 As Jehu came through the gate, she cried out, “Is all well, you Zimri, murderer of your master?” Jehu looked up to the window and shouted, “Who is on my side? Who?” At this, two or three eunuchs looked down toward him. “Throw her down,” he ordered. They threw her down, and some of her blood spurted against the wall and against the horses. Jehu trod over her body and, after eating and drinking, he said: “Attend to that accursed woman and bury her; for she was the daughter of a king.” But when they went to bury her, they found nothing of her but the skull, the feet, and the hands. They returned to Jehu, and when they told him, he said, “This is the word the Lord spoke through his servant Elijah the Tishbite: In the confines of Jezreel the dogs shall devour the flesh of Jezebel. The corpse of Jezebel shall be like dung in the field in the confines of Jezreel, so that no one can say: This was Jezebel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-kings-1515-16&quot;&gt;2 Kings 15:15-16&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of the acts of Shallum, with the conspiracy he carried out, these are recorded in the book of the chronicles of the kings of Israel. At that time, Menahem attacked Tappuah, all its inhabitants, and its whole district as far as Tirzah, because they did not let him in. He attacked them; he even ripped open all their pregnant women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;judith-136-10&quot;&gt;Judith 13:6-10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She went to the bedpost near the head of Holofernes, and taking his sword from it, she drew close to the bed, grasped the hair of his head, and said, “Strengthen me this day, Lord, God of Israel!” Then with all her might she struck his neck twice and cut off his head. She rolled his body off the bed and took the canopy from its posts. Soon afterward, she came out and handed over the head of Holofernes to her maid, who put it into her food bag. Then the two went out together for prayer as they were accustomed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-maccabees-618-23&quot;&gt;2 Maccabees 6:18-23&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eleazar, one of the foremost scribes, a man advanced in age and of noble appearance, was being forced to open his mouth to eat pork. But preferring a glorious death to a life of defilement, he went forward of his own accord to the instrument of torture, spitting out the meat as they should do who have the courage to reject food unlawful to taste even for love of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those in charge of that unlawful sacrifice took the man aside, because of their long acquaintance with him, and privately urged him to bring his own provisions that he could legitimately eat, and only to pretend to eat the sacrificial meat prescribed by the king. Thus he would escape death, and be treated kindly because of his old friendship with them. But he made up his mind in a noble manner, worthy of his years, the dignity of his advanced age, the merited distinction of his gray hair, and of the admirable life he had lived from childhood. Above all loyal to the holy laws given by God, he swiftly declared, “Send me to Hades!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-maccabees-1441-46&quot;&gt;2 Maccabees 14:41-46&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when the troops, on the point of capturing the tower, were forcing the outer gate and calling for fire to set the door ablaze, Razis, now caught on all sides, turned his sword against himself, preferring to die nobly rather than fall into the hands of vile men and suffer outrages unworthy of his noble birth. In the excitement of the struggle he failed to strike exactly. So while the troops rushed in through the doors, he gallantly ran up to the top of the wall and courageously threw himself down into the crowd. But as they quickly drew back and left an opening, he fell into the middle of the empty space. Still breathing, and inflamed with anger, he got up and ran through the crowd, with blood gushing from his frightful wounds. Then, standing on a steep rock, as he lost the last of his blood, he tore out his entrails and flung them with both hands into the crowd, calling upon the Lord of life and of spirit to give these back to him again. Such was the manner of his death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-maccabees-1530-35&quot;&gt;2 Maccabees 15:30-35&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Judas, that man who was ever in body and soul the chief defender of his fellow citizens, and had maintained from youth his affection for his compatriots, ordered Nicanor’s head and right arm up to the shoulder to be cut off and taken to Jerusalem. When he arrived there, he assembled his compatriots, stationed the priests before the altar, and sent for those in the citadel. He showed them the vile Nicanor’s head and the wretched blasphemer’s arm that had been boastfully stretched out against the holy dwelling of the Almighty. He cut out the tongue of the godless Nicanor, saying he would feed it piecemeal to the birds and would hang up the other wages of his folly opposite the temple. At this, everyone looked toward heaven and praised the Lord who manifests himself: “Blessed be the one who has preserved undefiled his own place!” Judas hung Nicanor’s head and arm on the wall of the citadel, a clear and evident sign to all of the Lord’s help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;psalm-38&quot;&gt;Psalm 3:8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arise, Lord! Save me, my God!&lt;br /&gt;
For you strike the cheekbone of all my foes;&lt;br /&gt;
you break the teeth of the wicked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;job-3633&quot;&gt;Job 36:33&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His thunder announces him&lt;br /&gt;
and he incites the fury of the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-kings-1824&quot;&gt;1 Kings 18:24&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The God who answers with fire is God.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;psalm-582-12&quot;&gt;Psalm 58:2-12&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you indeed pronounce justice, O gods;&lt;br /&gt;
    do you judge fairly you children of Adam?&lt;br /&gt;
No, you freely engage in crime;&lt;br /&gt;
    your hands dispense violence to the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wicked have been corrupt since birth;&lt;br /&gt;
    liars from the womb, they have gone astray.&lt;br /&gt;
Their venom is like the venom of a snake,&lt;br /&gt;
    like that of a serpent stopping its ears,&lt;br /&gt;
So as not to hear the voice of the charmer&lt;br /&gt;
    or the enchanter with cunning spells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O God, smash the teeth in their mouths;&lt;br /&gt;
    break the fangs of these lions, Lord!&lt;br /&gt;
Make them vanish like water flowing away;&lt;br /&gt;
    trodden down, let them wither like grass.&lt;br /&gt;
Let them dissolve like a snail that oozes away,&lt;br /&gt;
    like an untimely birth that never sees the sun.&lt;br /&gt;
Suddenly, like brambles or thistles,&lt;br /&gt;
    have the whirlwind snatch them away.&lt;br /&gt;
Then the just shall rejoice to see the vengeance&lt;br /&gt;
    and bathe their feet in the blood of the wicked.&lt;br /&gt;
Then people will say:&lt;br /&gt;
    “Truly there is a reward for the just;&lt;br /&gt;
    there is a God who is judge on earth!”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fight Oppression with Rest</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/fight-oppression-with-rest"/>
   <updated>2022-09-13T17:30:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/fight-oppression-with-rest</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Biblical symbolism, the number six (also 666) is a sign of evil. It often represents incompleteness or a perpetual state of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book of Genesis, God created the world in six days and then “blessed the seventh day and made it holy, because on it he rested from all the work of creating that he had done” (Genesis 2:3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number six signifies that rest has not yet come. That which makes work worth doing has not yet come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Ain’t no rest for the wicked.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Cage the Elephant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any practicing member of a Judeo-Christian religion knows that the week must contain a day of rest. Perhaps, though, in our culture we do not take this seriously enough. Moses, inspired by God, once said, “on six days work may be done, but the seventh day shall be holy to you as the sabbath of complete rest to the Lord. Anyone who does work on that day shall be put to death. You shall not even light a fire in any of your dwellings on the sabbath day” (Exodus 35:2-3).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moses makes it clear that “rest to the Lord” is vital.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;defining-rest&quot;&gt;Defining Rest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meaning of rest, in the commandment and in this writing, is not “sleep.” In the context of the commandment, Moses is contrasting rest with work. Rest is time spent not working. Rest is activity with no purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-the-best-rest-worship&quot;&gt;For the Best Rest, Worship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Leisure: The Basis of Culture&lt;/em&gt;, the German Catholic philosopher Josef Pieper writes about the importance of a holy day of rest. He points out that “the vacancy left by absence of worship is filled by mere killing of time and by boredom, which is directly related to inability to enjoy leisure; for one can only be bored if the spiritual power to be leisurely has been lost.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get at what Pieper is saying, it may be helpful to look at an observation about the Catholic liturgy made by the German Catholic theologian, Romano Guardini. He wrote that the liturgy “has one thing in common with the play of a child and the life of art — it has no purpose, but is full of profound meaning. It is not work, but play. To be at play, or to fashion a work of art in God’s sight — not to create but to exist — such is the essence of the liturgy” (The Spirit of the Liturgy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Romano is calling liturgy (formal worship) a form of play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pieper points out that it is best to use our leisure time to worship. If we don’t use it for that, then it is filled by boredom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we fill our leisure time with boredom, then we will not enjoy it. If we fill it with work, it is not leisure time at all. But if we fill it with worship, then we have tapped into the greatest rest known to man: divine play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a gist, the best way to rest is to play with God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Come to me, all you who labor and are burdened, and I will give you rest. Take my yoke upon you and learn from me, for I am meek and humble of heart; and you will find rest for yourselves. For my yoke is easy, and my burden light.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Jesus Christ, Matthew 11:28-30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fight-oppression-with-rest&quot;&gt;Fight Oppression with Rest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the most notorious men of the past couple hundred years have promoted work-without-rest as a virtue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Nazi Germany, a sign was placed above the entrance to the Dachau concentration camp that said, “Arbeit Macht Frei,” or “work sets you free” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the Soviet regime, a continuous working week, called the nepreryvka, was instilled. Workers were given two days off per week, but they were dispersed. Different people had off on different days so that industrial machinery was never left idle. This was detrimental to liturgical and family life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One complaint, published in a Soviet newspaper, said, “what is there for us to do at home if our wives are in the factory, our children at school and nobody can visit us? It is no holiday if you have to have it alone” &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sociologist Eviatar Zerubavel points out that it is possible that the nepreryvka’s detriment to religious and family life was intentional. Without a common resting day, it is easier for societal powers to divide and conquer because it is harder for the people to unite and stand up for themselves &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is harder for friendships to form, and friendships are a grave threat to tyrants. When two or more people find a common goal (this is how CS Lewis defines friendship), they are capable of revolution. Bill Gates and Paul Allen started Microsoft and changed the world. Steve Jobs and Steve Wozniak did the same when they started Apple. Revolutions begin with friendships. Taking away a common day of rest, thus straining friendships, is a great way for an absolutist state to maintain its power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another effect of the nepreryvka was that religious adherence was made impractical, if not impossible. Nobody could worship together on Sundays or feast days. This may have been intentional because the Communist Soviet Union saw religion as a threat to its own power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his book &lt;em&gt;The Undiscovered Self&lt;/em&gt;, Carl Jung points out that absolutist states, like the Soviet Union, see statistical reality - things which can be proven - as the only reality. Religion threatens that reality by claiming that there exist things which cannot be proven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Soviet rulers needed the state’s reality to be the only reality. That way, they could be the moral authority. That way, they could dictate each man’s moral decisions. They needed to be the holder of truth, above criticism. They needed individuals to outsource their moral decision-making to the state. And many are willing to do so because moral decision-making requires deep thinking and great responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, outsourcing one’s morals becomes a problem when the moral authority tells us to kill (like in the Rwandan Genocide), to turn in his brother if he speaks out against the state (like in the Soviet Union), or that some other evil is no longer evil (like abortion in our current state). This can cause men and women to act against their own consciences and commit atrocities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every individual succumbs to the state’s moral dictates, but enough might. Taking away the common day of rest makes it more difficult for people to come together, to debate and bond over moral discussions, to share ideas, and to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that a common tactic among tyrants is to not allow their victims proper rest. This enhances their power. It also means that rest is rebellion. Rest, especially through liturgical worship, is a way to fight the tyrants. If we don’t take our rest, then, we are giving in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-some-rest&quot;&gt;Get Some Rest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work is important, but so is a common day of rest. Cage the Elephant sang, “ain’t no rest for the wicked,” but I wonder if it’s the other way around. Something like, “rest, when done right, keeps us from the wicked,” or “rest keeps the wicked from us.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, it seems that rest, especially in the form of a common day of worship, keeps us whole (like the number seven in the Bible), and taking it away fractures us and we become exposed to grave danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this say about our current culture where everything is open 24/7, devices are sending us notifications at all hours, and productivity is all the rage?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I am going to go get some rest now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://academyofideas.com/2015/11/fear-and-social-control/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.grin.com/document/106155&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.biblegateway.com/versions/New-American-Bible-Revised-Edition-NABRE-Bible/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/worldviews/wp/2014/11/03/arbeit-macht-frei-the-notorious-nazi-sign-thieves-stole-from-a-concentration-camp/ &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;https://www.history.com/news/soviet-union-stalin-weekend-labor-policy &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Seek Moments, Not Minutes</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/minutes-vs-moments"/>
   <updated>2022-09-12T13:30:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/minutes-vs-moments</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;He spent his life in his lab,&lt;br /&gt;
Searching for a way&lt;br /&gt;
To live forever.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on his deathbed,&lt;br /&gt;
He wishes he had accepted fate&lt;br /&gt;
And lived while he had the chance.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Calendars and clocks exist to measure time, but that signifies little because we all know that an hour can seem as eternity or pass in a flash, according to how we spend it.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Michael Ende, Momo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before clocks, life was not measured so much in hours or minutes, and even days and years were less important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, life was measured in moments and seasons. Crops were planted not on a certain date, but when the oak tree’s leaves were the size of a squirrel’s foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have many reasons to be grateful for the invention of clocks, but when you’re on your death bed, would you rather count the number of minutes you lived or remember the moments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about your life so far in terms of time. It doesn’t seem very long does it? It goes by in a flash. But think about all the moments, the memories, and you have some substance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Feeling Bored or Burnt Out? Try Less Hyper-Stimulation</title>
   <link href="https://josephkreydt.github.io/cure-boredom-and-burnout"/>
   <updated>2022-01-22T16:50:47-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://josephkreydt.github.io/cure-boredom-and-burnout</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you often find yourself bored, burnt out or in a slump, limiting your exposure to hyper-stimulation might put you in a better state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a hyper-stimulating world. Our dopamine and serotonin receptors get slammed all day. Music on the commute, TV news in the office dining room, glowing computer screens everywhere, impatient emails, sugar-packed treats, coffee, coffee, coffee. After a while, we start to need hyper-stimulation to feel anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your receptors are burnt out. You want to do something different, but nothing seems interesting or exciting. You try star gazing, but you get outside and find yourself bored in just a couple minutes. You try yoga, but you lose focus with that too. You meet up with a couple friends. Sadly, the experience leaves you unsatisfied, bored. Life seems so bland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem could be that your friends are uninteresting, but it’s more likely that the situation didn’t give your brain’s receptors as much dopamine or serotonin as they’re used to. Your brain is accustomed to huge hits of caffeine and adrenaline and bright lights and loud noises, and…squirrel! The simple, quiet parts of life have become futile and dull because they don’t produce enough dopamine for your dopamine receptors which, thanks to the constant hyper-stimulation, have developed a very high tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aren’t meant to live like dogs, chasing the first thing that stimulates our minds. As humans, we are the only beings on Earth that can freely act against our animal instincts. That means we can make changes to improve our lives. It means you can climb out of that slump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You do have to climb a bit before you get to a better place. Because you will limit your exposure to hyper-stimulation, your boredom may increase at first. It will take time for your brain to adjust to a calmer, less stimulating lifestyle. However, when your brain recalibrates, the simple parts of life will once again bring you joy. Grabbing lunch with a good friend will make you happy. Seeing a cardinal in a tree during a snowy walk will cause your heart to flutter with excitement. Reading a book, an actual full-length book, will be possible once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reset your receptors, you need to remove or limit the amount of hyper-stimulation in your life. Here are some ways you can do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you feel bored, remember there is nothing wrong with sitting quietly, thinking of absolutely nothing, being with God, staring into space for a while. That boredom may just be your brain telling you to spend some time with your abba.
Spend 7 to 10 minutes every morning in silent prayer. Let your mind wander, but when it comes back, bring your focus back to God.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set time limits on your app usage; particularly on YouTube, dating apps, games, and social media as these are hyper-stimulating.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read for at least 20 minutes each night before you go to bed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cook dinner as slowly as possible. Don’t buy canned or pre-chopped vegetables. Spend time adding small garnishes that will make your food healthy and beautiful. Make everything from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you drink coffee, try making it weaker. That way you can still drink the same amount of delicious hot beverage, but with less stimulant (caffeine).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pick up a calm, slow, useless hobby like whittling, bicycle refurbishing, old-fashioned film developing, baking, or a musical instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do some yoga. It doesn’t have to be a specific routine. The basic idea of yoga is stretching mixed with deep breathing. Maybe your back is sore from standing at the Goo Goo Dolls concert all night, so you do some gentle back stretches. Maybe your calves and feet are tight from skiing all weekend, so you do some poses that stretch your legs and feet. All the while, take deep breaths as you move in and out of your stretches. If you need further guidance, take a yoga class or watch a couple yoga routine videos to get some ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Develop the virtue of patience by learning about and practicing good-will, humility, and complete trust and abandonment to God.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“God is secretly present with the suffering soul, and in reward for patience, it receives a secret strength and peace.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;William Ullathorne, Patience and Humility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resetting your receptors is about slowing and quieting down, and it might be the difference between a good life and a bad one. Life consists mostly of simple, bland moments. But bland does not mean tasteless. You just have to retrain your brain to taste them. You have to let those burnt out receptors heal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like switching from Oreos to oranges. Oreos are so packed with flavor that they make oranges seem dull, but when you’ve cut out the sugary sweets, you start to notice the subtle beauty contained in the fruit. Eventually, you come to actually prefer the fruit for its nuances of flavor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hyper-stimulating media, messages, and drinks that you consume are like Oreos. They make mild levels of stimulation seem boring. They make everyday life feel bland. It doesn’t have to be that way, though. The next time you catch yourself thinking, “nothing sounds interesting,” or “everything is boring,” consider subduing the hyper-stimulation in your life. Give yourself the opportunity to sense and enjoy the small gifts life has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
